[{"id": "5ad7e713b24f84e0b9f9ffb6", "question": "Who narrated the 1995 film \"Judge Dredd\"?", "answer": "James Earl Jones", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4d2", "question": "What does an Enigma machine do?", "answer": "Ciphers and deciphers messages", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a327", "question": "Who played the role of Jack Cates in the 1982 film \"48 Hrs.\"?", "answer": "Nick Nolte", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5cefc244948005ec986edce9", "question": "What Civil War anthem about a radical abolitionist inspired the US military anthem \"The Battle Hymn of the Republic\"?", "answer": "John Brown\u2019s Body", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c98a", "question": "What is Virga?", "answer": "Precipitation that doesn\u2019t reach the ground", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b35", "question": "What is the name of the winged horse of Greek mythology?", "answer": "Pegasus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fecd5b8ec223966ae8f88d1", "question": "The traditional Wimbledon colors are green, and what?", "answer": "Purple", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6014c95ffbde8045e48466eb", "question": "What is ferret saying when he performs a \"weasel war dance\"?", "answer": "\"Come play with me\" -- They sleep 15 hours per day.  When they are awake, they want to have fun and play with their human friends.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a4b", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"The Chocolate War\"?", "answer": "Robert Cormier", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fdfbb7a003d27d341092bc6", "question": "Where is the busiest airport in South America?", "answer": "S\u00e3o Paulo, Brazil", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391d3", "question": "Which famous actor voiced characters Lovelace and Ramon in the movie \"Happy Feet\"?", "answer": "Robin Williams", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c831", "question": "The \"Wandering\" species of what bird has the longest wingspan in nature?", "answer": "Albatross", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b20c", "question": "In which nation did the woven-yarn craft of \"God's eyes\" originate?", "answer": "Mexico", "category": "history"}, {"id": "601371c0138175489539638d", "question": "Which musician wrote the theme song for Johnny Carson's \"The Tonight Show\"?", "answer": "Paul Anka -- The song earned him massive royalties. According to Anka, he received $200 every time the song was played.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb32", "question": "What supermodel appeared dressed as George Washington on the cover of the premiere issue of \"George\" magazine?", "answer": "Cindy Crawford", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff0b06be662d71a53650fc8", "question": "The four routes through the Vatican Museums all end at what showstopper?", "answer": "Michelangelo\u2019s Creation of Adam", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3cd", "question": "What was the nationallity of Rasputin?", "answer": "Russian", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395a8", "question": "Who plays Ruby in the movie \"Cold Mountain\"?", "answer": "Renee Zellweger", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8f23301dd7bf43be5e80e", "question": "Why are most Muppets left-handed?", "answer": "Most muppeteers are right-handed", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a385", "question": "What is the capital of Estonia?", "answer": "Tallinn", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133918f", "question": "What time are all the clocks stuck on in the movie, \"Pulp Fiction\"?", "answer": "4:20", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601b4bef49076251badbeaca", "question": "Which U.S. President had his sister initially serve as First Lady?", "answer": "Grover Cleveland -- \u00a0His sister Rose Cleveland took on the duties of First Lady until he married his bride Frances in June 1886.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d9f", "question": "Who played the role of the US president in the movie \"Mars Attacks!\"?", "answer": "Jack Nicholson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfc5", "question": "Monza and Silverstone are venues for which sport?\u00a0", "answer": "Formula One Racing\u00a0", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b509", "question": "What two months are named for men?", "answer": "July and August", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c37", "question": "What is the name of the theme song from the TV show \"Friends\"?", "answer": "I'll Be There For You", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfa7", "question": "Which vegetable is the principal ingredient of rosti?\u00a0", "answer": "Potato\u00a0", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b36c", "question": "Laika was the first ever dog to do what?", "answer": "Go into space", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac1a", "question": "What year did the Seychelles gain their independence from the United Kingdom?", "answer": "1976", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339eae", "question": "What screen legend made her final appearance in the movie \"Ship of Fools\"?", "answer": "Vivien Leigh", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393f9", "question": "What actor/singer played the role of Right Arm in the 1997 movie \"The Fifth Element\"?", "answer": "Tricky", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f58", "question": "Which villain did Michael Shannon play in the 2013 movie \"The Man of Steel\"?", "answer": "General Zod", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58b8cc2f94b094db9158309d", "question": "Who was the first person to receive an \"Honorary Award\" at the Academy Awards?", "answer": "Charlie Chaplin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59071bde3745b36be73039c5", "question": "Who is Tony Chu\u2019s partner in the comic series \"Chew\"?", "answer": "John Colby", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f5c", "question": "What TV Show features the characters Fox Mulder and Dana Skully?", "answer": "The X-Files", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4de1406d333868d34d70e", "question": "Mustafa Kemal was the first President of which country?", "answer": "Turkey", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1e5", "question": "What was the second country to be featured in the \"Michelin Guide\" in 1904?", "answer": "Belgium", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59ae9380574a5ce6b56b823c", "question": "Who was the only man to knock out Muhammad Ali in a heavyweight title fight?", "answer": "Larry Holmes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6d4", "question": "What is the atomic number of iodine?", "answer": "53", "category": "science"}, {"id": "594d074f1a1c922dd1ac64b7", "question": "Who was both the 22nd and the 24th president of the United States?", "answer": "Grover Cleveland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d94", "question": "In the movie \"Charlie and the Chocolate Factory\", what animals dispose of Veruca Salt?", "answer": "Squirrels", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6017383744491cbd7c5a1796", "question": "What was the first U.S. state to ban billboards?", "answer": "Hawaii -- Billboards were banned in Hawaii in 1927.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c216", "question": "Which country were the 1948 Winter Olympic Games?", "answer": "Switzerland", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133962b", "question": "In what movie does Nicole Kidman play a ghost?", "answer": "The Others", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133960c", "question": "What pastime does Jeff \"The Dude\" Lebowski enjoy?", "answer": "Bowling", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f14", "question": "Who has been played in a movie by both Willem Defoe and James Caviezel?", "answer": "Jesus Christ", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdc15c4469bb8041d07a08c", "question": "What does \"dim sum\" mean in English?", "answer": "Touching heart", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c59", "question": "Who played the role of the bodyguard in the 1992 movie \"The Bodyguard\"?", "answer": "Kevin Costner", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c73a", "question": "What scientific principle allows a compass to work?", "answer": "Magnetism", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58f1678af7c52aae91cc07ba", "question": "What year did the Republic of Guinea-Bissau declare independance from Portugal?", "answer": "1973", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c196", "question": "Jake the Jailbird and Officer Mallory are characters that appear on which popular board game?", "answer": "Monopoly", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8e9", "question": "What island in Manila Bay was the site of a famous 1942 siege?", "answer": "Corregidor", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5b358b455db0d66a186cb556", "question": "In which football league does the team Rigas FS compete in?", "answer": "Latvian League", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fdab55f0b8cce1e6fda704c", "question": "Caff\u00e8 corretto is espresso \"corrected\" with what substance?", "answer": "Alcohol", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339639", "question": "Which Disney's cartoon character's love interest is named Captain Li?", "answer": "Mulan's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5f164acef9b80650dbe7f92c", "question": "How many British Admiral-class battlecruisers were cancelled in 1919?", "answer": "Three", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bea3", "question": "What biblical object may be a King James Version mistranslation of \"a robe with long sleeves\"?", "answer": "Joseph's \"coat of many colors\"", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa70", "question": "Strine is the vernacular language spoken in which country?", "answer": "Australia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "601737dc44491cbd7c5a178f", "question": "Which national park is widely recognized as the world's first national park?", "answer": "Yellowstone National Park -- President\u00a0Ulysses S. Grant signed the law making Yellowstone a national park on March 1, 1872.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea7dd3ff048f679a45abff", "question": "Anthophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Flowers", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b677", "question": "In archery, how many points are awarded for a bull's-eye?", "answer": "10", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea3f6fff048f679a45ab5e", "question": "Who was the Clark University physicist responsible for \"A Method of Reaching Extreme Altitudes\"?", "answer": "Robert Goddard", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133941b", "question": "Radiohead took the title of their album Paranoid Android from what book series?", "answer": "Hitchhikers Guide to the Galaxy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b309", "question": "Who was found in a \"spider hole\" on December 13, 2003?", "answer": "Saddam Hussein", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3bb", "question": "What two metals form the alloy white gold?", "answer": "Gold and silver", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b43", "question": "Taking advantage of a fad at the time, what song became a #1 hit for Ray Stevens in 1974?", "answer": "The Streak", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5906814dff9c0647b50a8093", "question": "How old was novelist Harper Lee at the time of her death in February, 2016?", "answer": "89", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bea4", "question": "What do sumo wrestlers throw into the ring to purify it before each bout?", "answer": "Salt", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f67", "question": "What pastime is the subject of the Christian Slater movie \"Gleaming the Cube\"?", "answer": "Skateboarding", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a35", "question": "What was William Shakespeare's hometown?", "answer": "Stratford-upon-Avon", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e36", "question": "What children's classic first chapter is titled \"Mowgli's Brothers\"?", "answer": "The Jungle Book", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a88", "question": "Which comic strip character is the owner of a dog named Otto?", "answer": "Sgt. Snorkel", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d98", "question": "What longtime London Symphony Orchestra conductor is also Woody Allen's father-in-law?", "answer": "Andre Previn", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdc6", "question": "What kind of flower does saffron come from?", "answer": "A crocus", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe1ef68145fb2946670738c", "question": "To any astronaut, what is an EVA?", "answer": "Extravehicular Activity", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d76", "question": "What beer-centric movie begins with the MGM lion belching rather than roaring?", "answer": "Strange Brew", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c480", "question": "What is a group of lions called?", "answer": "A pride", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5990b065b72eedf883a8c711", "question": "What is the abbreviation for trinitrotoluene?", "answer": "TNT", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be26", "question": "What bird did Ben Franklin suggest replace the bald eagle as a national emblem?", "answer": "The wild turkey", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb1f", "question": "What two-sport athlete didn't speak in his early 1990's Nike commercials because of his bad stutter?", "answer": "Bo Jackson", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600f71d5a9e54d890926f6e6", "question": "What Texas National Park is larger than the state of Rhode Island?", "answer": "Big Bend National Park -- Established in 1935, it is located along the Rio Grande River in southern Texas\u2019s Chihuahuan Desert.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339645", "question": "Where did Kevin's parents go for Christmas in the 1990 movie \"Home Alone\"?", "answer": "France", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339868", "question": "In Disney's \"Dumbo\", what kind of animal is Dumbos only friend?", "answer": "A Mouse", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd66029a5bfecdd737e0831", "question": "What percentage of Americans believe in Astrology", "answer": "26", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a655", "question": "What river was dammed to create Lake Champlain?", "answer": "None, it is a naturally occurring lake", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5b3231f9bf195a31e15d738a", "question": "What is the capital of Belize?", "answer": "Belmopan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9f2", "question": "How many US states border an ocean?", "answer": "23", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a978", "question": "What nation's legislative body is named The Riksdag?", "answer": "Sweden", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8b3", "question": "What is the main ingredient of guacamole?", "answer": "Avocados", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339210", "question": "Who played the role of the Joker in the 1989 \"Batman\" movie?", "answer": "Jack Nicholson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a11d", "question": "What Monty Python movie was banned in Norway?", "answer": "Life of Brian", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5902a125cad1ec93f27df774", "question": "What 1960\u2019s film with Michael Caine is often credited with aiding to the popularity of the French Press?", "answer": "The Ipcress File", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600240464be4723ccac22163", "question": "What is the name of the protagonist CIA analyst in Tom Clancy's novels?", "answer": "Jack Ryan", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5f164ce1f9b80650dbe7f930", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"Robinson Crusoe\"?", "answer": "Daniel Defoe", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c57", "question": "How many years were Whitney Houston and Bobby Brown married for?", "answer": "15", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefbe4a6ce05a3942286eec", "question": "In the film \"Red Dragon\", Francis Dolarhyde is obsessed with the painting of what English poet?", "answer": "William Blake", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5feddb8d6ce05a3942286d91", "question": "In \"Goodfellas\", what character did Robert De Niro portray?", "answer": "Jimmy Conway", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aaa5", "question": "Minsk is the capital of which European country?", "answer": "Belarus", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339080", "question": "Which writer adapted his own book for the 1989 film \"Pet Sematary\"?", "answer": "Stephen King", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5b7ff9b93a3a814d89068c56", "question": "What word describes one tenth of a nautical mile?", "answer": "Cable", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4b6", "question": "What is the only nation that borders both Israel and Libya?", "answer": "Egypt", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a56b", "question": "In 1620, the Pilgrims established the Plymouth colony in which present-day US state?", "answer": "Massachusetts", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac53", "question": "What did woman use to redden their lips during the era of Louis XIV?", "answer": "Lemons", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f13", "question": "Who has been played in a movie by both Cate Blanchett and Judi Dench?", "answer": "Queen Elizabeth I", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390e4", "question": "What does the middle initial stand for in Arthur C. Clarke's name?", "answer": "Charles", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "60077fd2bd51d85e222ab640", "question": "What was the official diagnosis when van Gogh was hospitalized in 1888?", "answer": "When Van Gogh was hospitalized on Christmas Eve 1888 in Ales, his official diagnosis was \"acute mania with generalised delirium\".", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a41", "question": "What \"couple\" would be known as Fischbacher and Horn if they went by their last names?", "answer": "Siegfried & Roy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392f2", "question": "In the movie \"Saving Private Ryan\", how many of the Ryan brothers were soldiers?", "answer": "Four", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c972", "question": "What colour are shelled pistachio nuts?", "answer": "Green", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339953", "question": "What is the name of the skunk in \"Bambi\"?", "answer": "Flower", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a67e", "question": "Which US state is home to Wind Cave?", "answer": "South Dakota", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae3a", "question": "What year did the American Revolutionary War begin?", "answer": "1775", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390c3", "question": "Who wrote the horror novel \"Dracula\"?", "answer": "Bram Stoker", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "601600fffe83fe1f2a824c5a", "question": "Why did famous Civil War photographer Mathew Brady go broke?", "answer": "No one wanted to remember the war", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c6b", "question": "What American folk tale character is based on a real\u00ad-life country preacher named John Chapman?", "answer": "Johnny Appleseed", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a64f", "question": "What city in Ohio is known as the \"Queen City\"?", "answer": "Cincinnati", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe766a0eec85e375820b285", "question": "Which Central American country's highest elevation point is Cerro Chirripo at 3,810 meters?", "answer": "Costa Rica", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a890", "question": "What city is home to The Willis Tower?", "answer": "Chicago", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6015effcfe83fe1f2a824c0f", "question": "Where was Christmas first celebrated?", "answer": "Rome -- it was first celebrated in 336 A.D.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6e2", "question": "What is the fastest animal on earth that runs on two legs?", "answer": "The ostrich", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398db", "question": "On what TV show did Amanda Blake play the role of saloon/brothel manager Miss Kitty Russell?", "answer": "Gunsmoke", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ec8", "question": "Mr. Giles French was a character on which US TV show in the late 1960's?", "answer": "Family Affair", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe656ccae7e414034b5aed2", "question": "During the Roman Triumvirate of 42 BCE, what region of the Roman Republic was given to Lepidus?", "answer": "Hispania", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd96e7c23c87fd04dd15e38", "question": "Which US state has the largest House of Representatives?", "answer": "New Hampshire", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9ed", "question": "How many vehicles did the original \"Gran Turismo\" video game have?", "answer": "140", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4cd", "question": "What seaport's name is Spanish for \"white house\"?", "answer": "Casablanca", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5febbc8b7e83c707845b214d", "question": "In what round of the NFL draft was quarterback Tom Brady selected in?", "answer": "Brady was the 199th pick in the sixth round of the 2000 NFL draft.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff7c1d22b316f4693fb679e", "question": "What is eaten traditionally in the UK the day before Ash Wednesday?", "answer": "Pancakes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600781c2bd51d85e222ab64f", "question": "How many versions of The Scream did Edvard Munch create?", "answer": "There are\u00a0five separate versions of the work - four paintings and a lithograph stone from which as many as 45 prints were made.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0d7", "question": "Who won an Oscar for his role in the film 'The Fugitive\"?", "answer": "Tommy Lee Jones", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c056", "question": "Which bird is the national bird of Israel?", "answer": "Hoopoe", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa50", "question": "What is the capital of Saint Vincent and the Grenadines?", "answer": "Kingstown", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c55b", "question": "How many carbon atoms are there in an aspirin molecule?", "answer": "9", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fdd60e10499cffc60b84239", "question": "Who wrote the 95 Thesis against the Catholic Church?", "answer": "Martin Luther", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b45", "question": "What does the Giant smell when he says \"Fee, Fi, Foe, Fum\"?", "answer": "The blood of an Englishman", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c25a", "question": "What is 400 in Roman numerals?", "answer": "CD", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe6aa3420565ad31a57c812", "question": "Who was President Gerald Ford's vice president?", "answer": "Nelson Rockefeller", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133caf4", "question": "Petroselinum crispum is the Latin name of which herb?", "answer": "Parsley", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe7cb17877e98cb97778a13", "question": "What name is given to 23.5 degrees north latitude?", "answer": "Tropic of Cancer", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ffa3a1cc73aa70ea0b70add", "question": "Toronto is on the shores of which Great Lake?", "answer": "Ontario", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5c3e9a0bebfabb9c85d8a977", "question": "What was the birth name of Bing Crosby?", "answer": "Harry Lillis Crosby Jr.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a52", "question": "What TV family had three sons named Brad, Mark, and Randy?", "answer": "The Taylor's from Home Improvement", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338983", "question": "Who is the tomboy main character in the book \"Little Women\"?", "answer": "Josephine (Jo) March", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b12c", "question": "Which Egyptian queen was married to pharaoh Akhenaten?", "answer": "Nefertiti", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be6f", "question": "What is the Minute Maid Park also known as?", "answer": "The Juice Box", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae8f", "question": "In which US state was President Bill Clinton born?", "answer": "Arkansas", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4eb", "question": "Which US state's name begins but doesn't end with the letter A?", "answer": "Arkansas", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "592eb197f83302ff91e464a9", "question": "Which early 20th century actor was known as the \"Latin Lover\"?", "answer": "Rudolph Valentino", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b76e", "question": "\"Old Scratch\" is a nickname for whom?", "answer": "Satan", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339392", "question": "Who played the role of Donnie Brasco in the movie of the same name?", "answer": "Johnny Depp", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe73572eec85e375820b24b", "question": "Who said, \"It\u2019s not enough that we do our best; sometimes we have to do what\u2019s required.\"?", "answer": "Winston Churchill", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339384", "question": "In the movie \"Stand By Me\", what cartoon character does Vern think can take Superman on?", "answer": "Mighty Mouse", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5aab2f0058d116dab4aecb45", "question": "What is the scientific method of dating tree rings called?", "answer": "Dendrochronology", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ca5", "question": "Who wrote the science-fiction novel \"The Time Machine\"?", "answer": "H. G. Wells", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fea7b2cff048f679a45abf3", "question": "What arctic sea whale has one long horn on its head?", "answer": "Narwhal", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133955a", "question": "What did the Wicked Witch of the West spell out with her broomstick in the sky in the 1939 film \"The Wizard of Oz\"?", "answer": "Surrender Dorothy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59ae9363574a5ce6b56b823a", "question": "What was Queen Victoria's first name?", "answer": "Alexandrina", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7a0", "question": "According to the Gospels, what did the Wise Men bring?", "answer": "Gold, Frankincense, and Myrrh", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339295", "question": "On what book series is the HBO TV series \"True Blood\" based?", "answer": "The Southern Vampire Mysteries", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aaa4", "question": "Minsk is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Belarus", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a40a", "question": "In which US state would you find the zip code 12345?", "answer": "New York", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cf2", "question": "Who plays the guitar introduction to Michael Jackson's hit \"Black or White\"?", "answer": "Slash", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "596df93df0cc2631d16a3c64", "question": "With which tune, that references the Fab Four, did Joe Diffie go to #1 in in 1996?", "answer": "\"Bigger Than The Beatles\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399ff", "question": "Who won an Oscar for his role as a drill sergeant in the movie \"An Officer and a  Gentleman\"?", "answer": "Louis Gossett Jr.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a119", "question": "Which classic Hollywood western is based on the film \"Seven Samurai\"?", "answer": "The Magnificent Seven", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb58", "question": "How many years are in a semicentennial?", "answer": "50", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd81c48d0de9af39e9d4682", "question": "Who was the first U.S. president to be photographed?", "answer": "John Quincy Adams", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c421", "question": "What movie award appears in the International Radio Alphabet?", "answer": "Oscar", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a359", "question": "What is the northernmost Scandinavian country?", "answer": "Norway", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a324", "question": "What was the full name of Mangum P.I.?", "answer": "Thomas Magnum", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58c8a79d90aac110e4167088", "question": "Under what name is Bulmers cider sold outside of Ireland?", "answer": "Magners", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b875", "question": "What make of car appears in the left foreground of the \"Abbey Road\" cover?", "answer": "Volkswagen", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339adb", "question": "What 1984 #1 song by the duo Wham! charted again in 2009 when covered by the group Seether?", "answer": "Careless Whisper", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390e1", "question": "What year was Ben Jonson's \"The Alchemist\" first performed?", "answer": "1610", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff511a7ff04d658268c92c8", "question": "Who was Canada's longest-serving prime minister?", "answer": "William Lyon Mackenzie King was Canada's longest serving prime minister at 21 years, 154 days, non-consecutively.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca77", "question": "An imperial fathom has how many yards?", "answer": "2", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339296", "question": "What is the most common swear word used in the TV series \"Battlestar Galactica\"?", "answer": "Frak", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ab99d0621a8909e5c332d3d", "question": "What two words start and end with \"und\"?", "answer": "Underground and underfund", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a236", "question": "Who recorded the album \"Business as Usual\" in 1981?", "answer": "Men at Work", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6014c829fbde8045e48466d1", "question": "The Horsehead Nebula can be found in what constellation?", "answer": "Orion", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe7cefa877e98cb97778a48", "question": "What is the lowest natural point on Earth?", "answer": "The Challenger Deep", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf60", "question": "A person who starts fires maliciously is known as a what?", "answer": "Arsonist", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397a8", "question": "What U.S. state gave the world Little Richard, Otis Redding and Gladys Knight?", "answer": "Georgia", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338db7", "question": "The Siege Perilous was the name for the empty seat where?", "answer": "The Round Table", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fea4583ff048f679a45ab94", "question": "What is an atom that has more electrons than normal referred to as?", "answer": "Negative ion", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ada6", "question": "The \"Italian Plague of 1629-31\" is also referred to as by what other name?", "answer": "Great Plague of Milan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe6a57c20565ad31a57c7cd", "question": "Which US president enjoyed a daily swim in the Potomac River?", "answer": "John Quincy Adams", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4e8", "question": "In which European city can you find the \"Mouth of Truth\"?", "answer": "Rome", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "600f71efa9e54d890926f6e7", "question": "What was the original name of Austin, the capital of Texas?", "answer": "Waterloo -- It was renamed after Texas leader Stephen F. Austin in 1839.  It became the state capital in 1845.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aacf", "question": "What is the second largest state in the US?", "answer": "Texas", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5c77d3d824f0f7a362efd554", "question": "Who was the last man from the Apollo program to have walked on the Moon?", "answer": "Eugene Cernan", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389e6", "question": "What Jules Verne adventurer fired his valet for bringing him shaving water two degrees below his requirement?", "answer": "Phileas Fogg", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe7c7ad877e98cb977789d5", "question": "What is the only country to lie entirely in the Alpine region?", "answer": "Lichtenstein", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6015e1d6fe83fe1f2a824b99", "question": "What was the \"The Blitz\"?", "answer": "A term used for Germany\u2019s bombing campaign on London", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b90a", "question": "What year did the famous Sears Tower in Chicago had its name changed to the \"Willis Tower\"?", "answer": "2009", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59ae94c7574a5ce6b56b824c", "question": "The cobnut is the fruit of what tree?", "answer": "Hazel", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fe2", "question": "According to the TV series, how many stories are there in \"The Naked City\"?", "answer": "Eight million", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba0f", "question": "What sport did Theodore Roosevelt propose to bad for being too violent?", "answer": "Football", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6d3", "question": "Which New England state does not have any ocean coastline?", "answer": "Vermont", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b788", "question": "What style of pants is named after an island in the Gulf of Naples?", "answer": "Capri pants", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b0c", "question": "What suit is the Queen is \"Alice's Adventures in Wonderland\"?", "answer": "Hearts", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "592eada3f83302ff91e4647f", "question": "What is the capital of the US state of Nebraska?", "answer": "Lincoln", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c36b", "question": "What was the main method of food preservation used by the Incas to store their potatoes?", "answer": "Freeze drying", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5fd", "question": "Which planet is known for its rings?", "answer": "Saturn", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339028", "question": "In Arthurian legend, who is the illegitemate son of Sir Lancelot?", "answer": "Galahad", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b86", "question": "In the comic strip Peanuts, what color is Woodstock?", "answer": "Yellow", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "60136fd7138175489539637d", "question": "Nolan Bushnell, the founder of Atari, is also the founder of what restaurant chain?", "answer": "Chuck E. Cheese -- It is famous for its pizza, animatronic shows, and electronic games - a feature pioneered by Nolan Bushnell.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe378ce0ada16518afdc054", "question": "Which popular Christmas song was originally written for a Broadway musical?", "answer": "\"White Christmas\"", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fc85458abc30a8194e188a7", "question": "A group of sharks is called what?", "answer": "A Shiver", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b692", "question": "Klaxon horns were used on what type of vehicle during World War II?", "answer": "Submarines", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9a7", "question": "What baseball player was nicknamed \"Joltin' Joe\" and the \"Yankee Clipper\"?", "answer": "Joe DiMaggio", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b51e", "question": "What gives Tonic Water its flavour?", "answer": "Quinine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7b0", "question": "What river forms most of the border between the US states Georgia and Alabama?", "answer": "Chattahoochee river", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe4e95806d333868d34d754", "question": "Where was the record for tallest wave ever surfed set?", "answer": "Nazar\u00e9, Portugal", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58ab0a2dbaab681b09292165", "question": "Who won the first season of American Idol?", "answer": "Kelly Clarkson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ec0", "question": "\"The Da Vinci Code\" repeats the myth that the glass pyramid in front of the Louvre consists of how many panes?", "answer": "666", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339aeb", "question": "What TV show's theme song was entitled \"Where Everybody Knows Your Name\"?", "answer": "Cheers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133887b", "question": "What book facilitated the ban of the pesticide DDT in 1972 in the U.S.?", "answer": "Silent Spring", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6f2", "question": "How many pieces does each player start a game of chess with?", "answer": "16", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58b3704f1c3f17ccc40c8e12", "question": "Which English Member of Parliament referred to the pub as \"the heart of England\"?", "answer": "Samuel Pepys", "category": "general"}, {"id": "601370cb1381754895396385", "question": "The Blondie song \"Call Me\" is featured in what movie?", "answer": "\"American Gigolo\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecc122ec223966ae8f8865", "question": "The 1982 football game that birthed \"The Play\", was between which schools?", "answer": "Stanford and Berkeley", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59071dc23745b36be73039dc", "question": "What is the nationality of the first woman in space?", "answer": "Soviet/Russian", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ae6", "question": "What real-life woman, the subject of a 2000 film, won the Miss Pacific Coast beauty pageant in 1981?", "answer": "Erin Brockovich", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c869", "question": "What tree's edible seeds were once used to weigh diamonds?", "answer": "The carob tree's", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4f0", "question": "What must a Las Vegas blackjack dealer do when they reaches 16?", "answer": "Take a card", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a777", "question": "What US state\u2019s highest peak is Mt. Elbert?", "answer": "Colorado's", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe937526bd93ce3a4e5f66b", "question": "In the weasel family, which marine mammal is the heaviest member?", "answer": "Sea otter", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ab99aef21a8909e5c332d26", "question": "Who was John Lennon married to?", "answer": "Yoko Ono", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be56", "question": "What common lasagna ingredient is actually a by-product of mozzarella?", "answer": "Ricotta", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f8f", "question": "Who composed the opera \"A Village Romeo and Juliet\"?", "answer": "Frederick Delius", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5c90cf4b52800b05cac20f08", "question": "What US state is nicknamed \"The Ocean State\"?", "answer": "Rhode Island", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394a9", "question": "Who starred as John Drake in the TV show \"Secret Agent\"?", "answer": "Patrick McGoohan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600243ad4be4723ccac22199", "question": "Which American author wrote the novel \"The Color Purple\"?", "answer": "Alice Walker", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d47", "question": "What folk hero is said to live in the Sherwood Forest?", "answer": "Robin Hood", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e0", "question": "Who wrote the first three books of the \"Millennium\" novel series?", "answer": "Stieg Larsson", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389b5", "question": "What Shakespeare play if \"All the world's a stage\"?", "answer": "As You Like It", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdfa", "question": "Besides aces, what was the other pair in Wild Bill Hickok's \"dead man's hand\"?", "answer": "Eights", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b3589e25db0d66a186cb54f", "question": "French fries are claimed to have originated in which country?", "answer": "Belgium", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd6a2da6c0f9723ab15cb47", "question": "Who was the first president to receive full-time Secret Service protection?", "answer": "Theodore Roosevelt", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6015ea40fe83fe1f2a824bef", "question": "In 2007, purported remains of what saint were found to be from an Egyptian mummy instead?", "answer": "Joan of Arc", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3a9", "question": "What element is given the symbol \"I\"?", "answer": "Iodine", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af68", "question": "Who did George Washington name as vice president?", "answer": "John Adams", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b88", "question": "What Looney Toons cartoon character often used the catchphrase \"Thufferin' Thuccotash\"?", "answer": "Sylvester the cat", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395a1", "question": "The Broadway show \"Movin' Out\" was based on songs written by what singing star?", "answer": "Billy Joel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f1b", "question": "Who has been played in a movie by both John Gavin and Rex Harrison?", "answer": "Julius Caesar", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58ec26ac8dc25ca9e12ef64e", "question": "What is a male goose called?", "answer": "Gander", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d7c", "question": "Who was the real-life model for the character of Doris Mann in the novel \"Postcards from the Edge\"?", "answer": "Debbie Reynolds", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ffb68455dad637d903c8841", "question": "Which country, other than Switzerland, uses the Swiss franc?", "answer": "Liechtenstein", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb4c", "question": "What sign are you if you were born on Valentine\u2019s Day?", "answer": "Aquarius", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b7ab8646490a8cc1a6e528c", "question": "What type of bear has a clear eyelid?", "answer": "Polar Bears", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c88d", "question": "What does the Holmes and Rahe scale measure?", "answer": "Stress caused by life events", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cbd", "question": "What famous museum was once called the Musee' Napoleon?", "answer": "The Louvre", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fecdd0dec223966ae8f88fd", "question": "Which Yankee was nicknamed \"The Iron Horse\"?", "answer": "Lou Gehrig", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b114", "question": "What Spanish explorer became the first governor of Puerto Rico in 1508?", "answer": "Juan Ponce de Leon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339886", "question": "What type of radiation gives The Hulk his powers?", "answer": "Gamma", "category": "entertainment"}]